So in this account,
we're going to make sure to spend
the least amount of money or no money,
and I will let you know when something
will cost you some money.
But nonetheless, it is a good idea
to set up a billing budget
so that we know when we go over spending some money
and we can get alerted in case of that.
So what I'm going to do is click on My Account,
and then click on My Billing Dashboard.
Now as you can see, I need permissions,
and this is because I'm logged in
as an IAM user on my account,
and we need to change something on the root account
before we get access with IAM users, even administrators,
to the Billing & Cost Management Dashboard.
So to solve this I logged in as my root account,
as you can see, now it just says my account number,
it doesn't say the IAM user,
so I'm logged in as my root account,
and then I click on My Accounts.
So you need to be your root account to do this.
You scroll down and you're going to find this one setting
called IAM User and Role Access to Billing Information.
And we'll edit this
and we'll activate IAM access,
and this will allow IAM users who are administrators
to access billing data.
If you don't want that,
you can also set up a billing alarm
using the root account, if you wanted to.
But I want to show you how to set up a billing alarm
using an IAM user,
in case this is something you wanted to do.
So once this setting is activated,
you can go back into your IAM user,
and then refresh this page.
So here we are in the AWS Billing Dashboard home,
and this is where you can see the charges for your month.
We do the best to remain within the free tier,
but sometimes, if you have any charge,
you would see it here,
and then let me show you
how you can find the source of your charge.
So if you go on the left hand side into Bills,
and you are on this Bills page,
just click on try the new bills page experience
to get to this interface.
Okay, so once we are here in this interface,
you would see your grand total,
and then you can scroll down
and you can go to Charges by Service.
And this is to see which service
is incurring you some charges.
So for example, if I go and scroll down
and go into my Elastic Compute Cloud service,
I can see that 62 cents were incurred
in the US East, Northern Virginia region.
So I click on it and open this in a new page.
And on the new UI, I see that, yes, this is the charge,
and it comes from the EBS part of it.
So this is the Usage Description,
and it says that I've been using
a six gigabyte month of the gp2 type of EBS volume.
So this information is enough for me
to figure out that I've probably left a volume unused
in my accounts.
So I would go into the Elastic Compute Cloud console
I would switch to the Northern Virginia region,
using the top right hand side dropdown,
and then I would go into the EBS section
and delete this volume that's been incurring charges to me.
So it's up to you, of course, to debug your own costs,
and so this is the way you would do it.
Also, if you go over the free tier,
this is going to be on the left hand side.
So if you go on the left hand side,
you will see all your services,
as well as what is the free tier usage
and your current usage.
So you know right away if you are, for example,
at 100% of your free tier
or if you're about to hit it and so on,
so this really helps you to understand
what you've been doing wrong as well.
Now to get alerts about your upcoming costs,
the best thing to do is to go into creating an AWS budget.
So I am now in the budget console,
and I'm going to create a budget in here
so that we can track our cost
and we can make sure we receive alerts
if we're about to hit our limits.
So here are some templates,
so we have user templates,
and then we can go into a zero spend budget
that creates a budget that notifies you
once your spending exceeds the free tier limits.
So in that case, I will have my Zero Spend Budget,
this is good.
And we can have email recipients,
so stephane@example.com.
And then you will be notified via email
for any spend is incurred.
So let's create this budget,
and that's one budget right here.
And then, I can create a second budget if I wanted to.
And again, we're going to use a simplified template
and we're going to go for monthly cost budgets
and this is the amount of cost
that we want to budget for our cloud.
So for example, I can say that
I don't wanna spend any more than $10, so I put 10 here.
And then, the email recipients,
so again, stephane@example.com,
and then I will be notified actually
if my actual spend reaches 85% or 100%,
or if my forecasted spend is expected to reach 100%.
So this is another way to set the budgets,
and let's click on Create Budgets, and we're good to go.
So that's it, of course,
my zero spend budget has been exceeded
because I am already in an account
that has been some charges, so as you can see,
we have an alert and I would receive an email.
And so, that's it,
with this you know how to explore your bills,
you know how to explore your free tier,
you know how to set up a budget
so that you can track your cost
for monthly budget costs or for free tier costs.
And that should be enough for you
to control your costs in this course.
Okay, I hope you liked this lecture,
and I will see you in the next lecture.